Encoded by hd4u
( static buzzing ON device )
( speaking norwegian )
( static SQUEALlNG )
( BOTH laughing )
Stop !
( BRAKES SCREECH )
( speaking norwegian )
( PULSlNG )
( cracking )
( ALL screaming )
( groaning )
( rhythmic BEEPlNG )
( music playing OVER HEADPHONES )
GUARD : Kate .
Shit .
Sorry , Kate . These fellas said that you 've been expecting them .
Of course . Thanks , Hank .
Thanks .
( CHUCKLES ) Hey .
You forgot , didn 't you ?
No , no .
I just ...
Yeah .
He just wanted to ... Actually , this is him . Okay .
I 'm Dr. Sander Halvorson .
Kate Lloyd .
Yes . Do you know who I am ?
I do .
Adam told me a little bit about you as well .
He says you specialize in vertebrate paleontology .
Primarily , yes .
And obviously you 've extracted specimens from pack ice .
I 've worked on several cold-weather digs .
Good .
Um ...
An old friend of mine , a colleague from Oslo ,
runs a geological research station in Antarctica .
Forty-eight hours ago , his team found something
quite remarkable .
Really ?
What 'd they find ?
We 're flying down there tomorrow evening to examine the site
and I need a paleontologist .
Doctor , I 'm sure you can understand
that I need to know a little bit
about what it is I 'm being asked to dig up .
There 's a structure .
A structure ?
Yes . In Antarctica ?
And a specimen .
That 's all I can tell you .
And I guess I don 't have any time to think about this ?
No , I 'm sorry . I need your answer right now .
Well ...
I 'm in .
Great .
Adam will get you the details of our departure .
SANDER : I 'll see you in the car .
Yes , of course . Thank you .
Adam .
What the hell is it ?
( SCOFFS ) You now officially know as much as I do .
But I 'll tell you one thing . I have worked for that guy for three years
and I have never seen him this excited .
CARTER : Hey .
She US ?
Mmm-hmm .
( GRlGGS snoring )
Look at this guy .
How is that even humanly possible ?
I was hoping maybe you could help me with something .
I can 't seem to get a hold of a newspaper that 's not , you know ,
three weeks old , and I 'm a man in desperate need of certain information .
Carter , don 't do this to yourself , man .
And what information would that be ?
I wanna know how the Cavaliers are doing .
Hmm . I don 't follow football .
It 's a basketball team .
They play basketball .
Barely .
They 're the Cavaliers , man .
( chuckling )
Sorry I couldn 't help you .
That 's all right .
Hey , listen , so you guys know , whatever you all are doing ,
you might wanna wrap it up in a couple of days .
Yeah ? Why 's that ?
There 's a storm moving in .
A nasty one .
Good morning , Griggs .
Yeah , he 's right .
And the last place that you wanna be
is cooped up with a dozen Norwegian guys .
( chuckling )
Trust me .
Base in sight at my one o 'clock .
This is H3 Sea King inbound for Thule . Do you copy ?
colin ON radio : Hello , H3 Sea King . Please approach from the west .
That path is clear .
JAMESON : Throttle coming back .
CARTER : Good to go , Griggs .
Dr. Halvorson ?
Yes .
Welcome to Thule .
Thank you .
Edvard asked you to go to the site right now .
Lars is gonna drive you .
LLOYD : Hi . Hi , welcome .
Please go in the Spryte . Thanks .
( LARS speaking norwegian )
( EDVARD SPEAKS norwegian )
SANDER : Edvard !
( groaning )
( speaking norwegian )
Yeah , this is Kate Lloyd .
Columbia paleontology .
Welcome .
Adam Finch , my research assistant .
Welcome . Hi .
This is Edvard , my good friend .
This is some of my team . This is Karl and Juliette .
Both geologists . Hi .
Welcome .
Okay .
Let me show you why you flew
1 0,000 miles .
Holy shit .
We estimate it 's been here approximately 1 00,000 years .
We picked up a signal transmitting .
Some kind of distress call , perhaps .
Incredible .
EDVARD : We think the signal got triggered
when the survivor exited the craft .
Survivor ?
SANDER : My God .
How long will it take to get out ? Do you know , Kate ?
Assuming you have the right equipment , I 'd say ,
maybe a half a day .
Good .
( speaking norwegian )
LLOYD : Uh , the ice ,
I should ask you , how fragile is it ?
It 's not in the fracture zone , so there 's very little risk of fissuring .
And the ice is quite dense , so we think
we can get it out in one piece .
Good .
A rough estimate is about six by 1 2 feet , three and a half feet high .
Probably someplace around three and a half ...
That 's good .
Make sure that everyone stays off the radio .
We don 't want any information out .
And the crane , do we have something that 's
appropriate for this ?
Yeah , it 's already there . It 's all set up .
I 'm Peder , by the way .
Peder . Nice to meet you .
So you 've got it all taken care of .
I don 't think you really need me .
( ALL LAUGH )
What about him ? is he completely disinterested or ...
KARL : Oh , that 's Lars .
He doesn 't understand English , but he 'll work like a bear .
henrik : And as you can see from the scans ,
the ship carved a 200-meter tunnel into the ice .
Wow .
So let me get this right .
You crash into a glacier ,
and then without enough information ,
you leave the cozy confines of your ship ?
Maybe it was hurt and wanted to find someplace warm .
I guess it didn 't find it .
( wind whistling )
The first night is hard .
I 'm sorry . I don 't mean to keep you up .
No , no , it 's fine .
We 'll never look at them the same again .
ADAM : ... 93 pounds ...
What do you need for a transport weight ?
To cut it down to a portable weight ,
we 'll have to take it from here to here .
Start with four inches or so .
I never believed in this shit .
I always did .
We all set ?
Nearly there .
Good .
But before we do , I 'm going to take a tissue sample .
Do you really think that 's a good idea ?
Yes , I do .
The conditions are so unpredictable
and we don 't have the proper equipment .
Sterilization is an issue .
Edvard , what do you have in the way of a small diameter drill ?
EDVARD : Up to 30 millimeters .
Very good .
SANDER : I think somewhere around here .
Kate .
Just a second .
In the future , don 't contradict me
in front of those people again .
I just thought I 'd ...
You 're not here to think .
You 're here to get this thing safely out of the ice .
I hope we understand each other .
( DOOR OPENS )
( DOOR CLOSES )
( cracking )
( SQUlSHlNG )
( indistinct talking )
( ALL exclaim )
Here you are .
So , have you ever tasted this before ?
No , I haven 't . It tastes very bad .
SANDER : Gentlemen , ladies .
After a short but thorough investigation
of our visitor ,
I can say , unequivocally ,
that I have never seen anything on any cellular level
like what we have in that other room .
And the impact of this find will be felt for thousands of years .
From this point on ,
the world as we know it has forever been altered .
( dripping )
You , my friends , will all be immortalized
as the people who made this discovery .
( speaking norwegian )
( laughing )
( ALL cheering )
Thank you .
( singing )
You think they 're gonna pay a bonus for bringing home an alien
instead of core samples ?
You got anything better than this cough syrup ?
Hey , Griggsey . Yeah ?
You wanna go out and get the captain 's stash ?
Sure . No problem .
I 'm on it .
( ALL singing )
( DOG barking AND whining )
Where 'd I put those bottles ?
( humming )
( WHlMPERlNG )
( GROWLlNG )
PEDER : Boo ! Jesus !
( chuckling )
( breathing heavily )
Screw you , man .
Son of a bitch .
( CREATURE growling )
( barking )
( ALL singing )
It broke out !
( LAUGHTER )
Cuckoo !
It ain 't a damn joke , man !
The frigging thing 's alive !
I was in the room , man , looking at the ice ,
the frigging thing jumped out !
EDVARD : We will search in groups of two and three .
The entire camp .
If you find it , call out .
Don 't attempt anything on your own .
And be careful .
We don 't know what condition it 's in .
( speaking norwegian )
Griggs .
You leave that open ?
I don 't remember .
Shit .
Hey , just be careful , man .
That thing jumped through the fucking roof .
( speaking norwegian )
Jesus Christ .
( animal WHlMPERlNG )
( speaking norwegian )
Shh !
( SHUSHlNG )
( cracking )
( CREATURE WHlMPERlNG )
( SCREECHES )
( GRUNTS )
( screaming )
OLAV : Help ! Over here !
Help !
Somebody !
Over here !
Where ?
It attacked Henrik !
Come on !
( CREATURE growling )
ln there !
Oh , God , somebody do something !
Shoot it ! Shoot the fucker !
( SCREECHlNG )
( speaking norwegian )
Hey !
( SQUEALlNG )
No , no , no , no !
We gotta burn that fucker , man ! Burn it !
Throw it ! Throw it !
( CREATURE screeching )
( LARS shouting in norwegian )
( SPHYGMOMANOMETER puffing )
( air hissing )
KARL : His blood pressure is low .
( sobbing )
Henrik had two small children .
SANDER : Yes , it 's horrible .
It was a horrible tragedy .
We are all shocked at what happened to Henrik .
But with due respect , we need to examine
the remains before it all disintegrates .
Hey , that was a man . Not remains .
No , I 'm talking about the creature .
And I 'm sure we 're all aware of the importance of this discovery .
This may be the first and only time mankind
has been visited by an alien life form .
And as scientists , we 're obliged to study it .
Didn 't work out so well the last time , did it ?
CARTER : I think you should destroy it .
Completely .
I think you 've contributed enough to this endeavor .
Really ?
Listen , your guy Olav back there , he 's in bad shape .
Now , we 're gonna fly him back to McMurdo at sun up
and take him to the military hospital .
And what are you going to tell them ?
I 'm gonna tell them the truth , as crazy as it sounds .
( SANDER speaking norwegian )
( cracking )
( air hissing )
SANDER : Kate .
Can you help here ?
Come on .
Pull that side open .
( GAGGlNG )
His face is encased in some type of amniotic sac .
( DOOR BANGS SHUT )
And the tissue
looks almost new .
What was it doing to him ?
It appears it was absorbing him .
Some type of digestion .
It 's fascinating .
It is fascinating .
( sighs )
Hey .
What 's the matter ? Are you okay ? I 'm fine .
You sure ? Yeah , I 'm okay .
You need something ?
No , no. I 'm okay .
What is this ?
It looks like a titanium plate .
It 's used to reinforce broken bones , compound fractures .
Yeah , that 's right .
Henrik broke his arm last year .
He had to go to Argentina to get it set .
So if this was in his arm , what 's it doing out of him now ?
That 's a good question .
What are you doing ?
I took a sample of Henrik 's tissue .
I want to find out what this thing was doing to him .
I think you should take a look at this .
ADAM : These cells aren 't dead .
That 's not possible .
It looks like the alien cells are somehow
attacking Henrik 's cells and then they ...
What is that ? It 's like they 're transforming into ...
They 're imitating his cells .
Okay , I don 't know if that 's what I 'm seeing , but ...
They 're imitating him .
JAMESON : Place is giving me the creeps , man .
CARTER : No kidding .
We 're getting out of here not a moment too soon .
Hey , yo , did you get that other thing ?
CARTER : Yeah , all I could carry .
EDVARD : It 's going to be okay , Olav . A doctor will see you at McMurdo .
OLAV : Okay .
CARTER : Kate .
Hey .
We 're leaving .
If the weather holds up , we 'll be back with help as soon as we can .
Okay .
All right .
Keep him warm . I will .
Come on , let 's go .
Sit down there .
There you go .
Let 's get the hell out of here .
( helicopter retreating )
Carter !
Carter , wait ! Come on !
She 's flagging us down .
What 's wrong ?
They shouldn 't leave .
JAMESON : Carter .
Let 's just get out of here , man .
All right , fuck it . We 're landing .
Shit .
Let 's take her down .
is there something wrong ?
Uh ... No , no , everything 's fine .
They probably just forgot something .
We 'll be in the air in no time . Okay ?
Don 't worry .
Hang in there .
( SHlVERlNG )
( cracking )
( SCREECHlNG )
( screaming )
LLOYD : Something 's wrong .
( explosion )
Hailing McMurdo or any ears on emergency channel ,
do you copy ? Over .
I repeat , this is Thule Station .
They crashed here , right behind this ridgeline .
It 's impossible to reach them .
ADAM : This doesn 't make any sense .
They had plenty of visibility , right ?
We 're not going after them ? Shouldn 't we try ?
We need our chopper to even get close to them ,
and that 's refueling in Halley .
This can 't be a coincidence .
Radio 's dead . It 's fucking dead .
The incoming storm .
( CURSES in norwegian )
There 's too much interference .
( speaking norwegian )
Colin , Lars , get your gear .
We 'll take a snowcat to the next base . Lars .
( speaking norwegian )
I don 't think that 's a good idea .
And why is that ?
Because no one can leave this camp
until we know more about what 's going on here .
I make decisions about this camp .
I know , Edvard , but ...
Why did you flag down that helicopter ?
Because I thought it was in danger .
Why ?
I took a sample of Henrik 's blood .
And I saw that the alien cells were still alive .
They were alive and they were copying Henrik 's cells .
Replicating them .
Adam saw it , too .
is that true ?
I don 't know . I don 't know what we saw .
We saw something .
I don 't understand . What are you saying ?
That this thing can and probably has
replicated a person .
( ALL talking AT ONCE )
Yeah . Okay , okay . Kate , Kate .
Okay . Kate .
This is not the time to be yelling , " Fire . "
Let 's stop , gather our thoughts ,
and discuss this in private .
We don 't need any private meetings , Doctor .
We all want the fucking information .
There 's more .
What are those ?
I think they 're fillings from someone 's teeth .
I found them by a puddle of blood in the shower .
A puddle of blood ?
It can clone cells , but not inorganic material .
It couldn 't copy these , so it spit them out .
We 've wasted too much time already . Lars ...
Listen .
When I went back to check it , someone had cleaned up the blood .
Someone had wiped it away .
All right ? So whatever it is ,
it is still here .
I 've heard enough .
Lars , Colin , get your gear . Ten minutes .
Please , Edvard .
You can 't leave .
You can 't leave . You don 't know what we 're dealing with .
Well done .
Kate .
I don 't know if I should be speaking about this .
I don 't wanna get anyone in trouble , but ...
Speaking about what ?
You were saying
about someone cleaning up the blood from the shower ,
that someone here may not be themselves ?
Juliette , please .
What did you see ?
After the crash , I think I saw Colin coming from the showers .
He was holding something .
It could have been a towel or a rag , something to clean up .
Kate , I can 't say for sure , but it 's just the ...
( DOOR CLOSES )
He 's leaving with Edvard .
We can 't let him go .
We can 't let any of them go .
I know where they keep the keys for the vehicles .
Okay .
Where are they ?
In that drawer .
This one ? Yes .
How many am I looking for ?
Five .
There 's three and four .
You said there were five ?
( CREATURE SQUEALlNG )
Run !
( screaming )
Kate , what happened ?
Karl ! It got Karl ! It got Karl !
( CREATURE growling )
Kate ...
Burn it !
( SQUEALlNG )
( screaming )
( speaking norwegian )
What the fuck 's happening to us ?
It attacks its prey ,
copies it perfectly ,
and then hides inside it ,
waiting .
is it still among us ?
It could be any of us .
PEDER : We 've gotta get out of here .
Yeah . Right now .
Then you could be getting in a vehicle with it .
You 'd be alone .
Vulnerable .
That 's exactly what it wants .
Not to mention you 'd be giving it a way out of here .
A way to spread .
It 's like a virus .
So what do we do with any virus ?
Quarantine .
We isolate it and then we kill it .
Yeah .
We have to rely on science .
Exposing our uncontaminated blood to the cells of the creature
might create a reaction of some kind .
So we take blood samples from everybody .
Yeah , and we test each one of them .
Yes . Adam and I can do that .
Okay .
Lars and I will disable the vehicles .
We have to trust in this plan .
It 's our only chance of making it through this .
LLOYD : is that it ?
( speaking norwegian )
No more vehicles ?
Okay .
What ?
( LARS SPEAKS norwegian )
EDVARD : is everything all right ?
Yes .
Yes , everything 's fine .
Good .
( speaking norwegian )
Kate , we should go .
The storm is getting worse .
LLOYD : Who is that ?
JONAS : Hurry , they 're coming !
( BOTH GRUNT )
PEDER : The Americans .
It 's impossible for a human to survive that crash .
We should burn them .
Right here , right now .
( yelling in norwegian )
lt could be murder .
It could be survival , Kate .
Yes , but we don 't have to kill them . All right ?
We can just lock them up until Sander 's test is ready .
Please .
CARTER : So this is a good idea ?
Locking us up ?
You need our help .
( speaking norwegian )
Okay .
Kate .
A bunch of scientists , they can 't handle what we saw in that chopper .
For all we know , you could be one of those things .
It is pretty hard to believe you both walked away from that crash .
Yeah , I get that . I do , but ...
We 're preparing a test ,
and then we figure out who 's who .
It 's all I can offer you right now .
( GLASS shattering )
( PEDER shouting )
( coughing )
JONAS : Someone sabotaged it .
There 's nothing left . Nothing .
Now there 's no test .
How could this happen ?
It was no accident .
You .
You were in there with it .
You were the last one .
Why are you accusing me ?
Why not ?
He 's got something to hide .
What are you , an asshole ?
I was the one working on the test . I left for two minutes !
You just don 't want us to know the truth , do ya ?
Bullshit ! Don 't tell me to fucking calm down !
Calm down ! Calm down !
This is a goddamn fucking nightmare !
There might be another way .
I think there might be
another way to tell .
Peder , give me your flashlight .
Now tell Lars to open his mouth .
Huh ?
Tell him to open his mouth .
( speaking norwegian )
Good .
Lars has fillings .
So he 's human . It can 't imitate inorganic material .
See ?
Good .
Open .
( LARS speaking norwegian )
Okay .
Okay . Good .
Right now it 's at least something .
A way to eliminate some of us .
So I 'm gonna get killed because I floss ?
Nobody 's getting killed .
Kate .
( speaking norwegian )
Kate , come on .
Kate .
Just do it .
Open .
Just go stand over there .
You know as well as I do , there are too many variables .
Open your mouth .
Open your mouth !
They 're porcelain .
Go stand by Adam .
Anyone else with porcelain fillings ?
Or clean teeth ?
This is bloody absurd .
( speaking norwegian )
This is wrong .
Jonas , you and Lars go out ,
get Carter and Jameson and bring them in here .
We 'll check them , too .
But why don 't we just leave them where they are ?
They can 't do anything .
We need to know .
( speaking norwegian )
( DOOR OPENS )
Yeah .
( speaking norwegian )
Lars .
Lars !
Lars ! Lars !
Peder .
( speaking norwegian )
Whatever they 're saying , right now it doesn 't matter .
You can 't trust them .
( banging ON DOOR )
Watch them .
( banging continues )
JONAS : Kate !
Come on !
Where are they ? Where are the rest ?
They attacked him !
LLOYD : Who ? They got Lars !
Peder !
( speaking norwegian )
What happened ? Peder , keep them back .
Stay on them , Peder !
We don 't know if we can trust them !
( ALL arguing )
Stay on them ! Stay on them , Peder !
( GLASS shattering )
They 're inside .
Hey !
Calm down ! What have you done with Lars ?
I said calm down !
Where the fuck is Lars ?
Drop it .
Somebody tell him !
( speaking norwegian )
Put it down !
Peder . Peder .
Okay .
I just want to check my friend , okay ?
It 's okay .
JAMESON : He was gonna fire .
( TRlCKLlNG )
lt 's gonna blow ! Watch out !
( GRUNTS )
( groaning ) JONAS : Edvard ?
Edvard ?
Pick him up .
Okay .
JAMESON : Get down . Get down .
You .
Yeah , you , help him !
All right , show yourselves .
Right fucking now !
Everybody in the rec room .
JAMESON : Pick him up . Come on .
Sit down .
Not all of us are human .
Just put him over there on the couch .
( CREATURE SQUEALlNG )
( screaming )
Get it off !
What the fuck is this shit , man ?
Carter !
Carter , burn it , man !
There 's something wrong with it ! Fuck !
God damn it , Carter , burn it !
( SCREAMS )
Shit ! Carter , table !
Carter !
CARTER : Something 's wrong with the pressure .
It 's got air in the pipe !
Watch out !
We gotta get the air out !
( screaming )
( GROWLlNG )
No ! No !
Burn it !
( HlSSlNG )
( yelling )
( GROWLlNG in distance )
( MUFFLED WHlMPERlNG )
I 'm with you , buddy .
( gasping )
Carter ?
Hey .
Are you okay ?
Yeah .
Are you ?
Not yet I 'm not .
We find it and we kill it .
( CREAKlNG )
( GROWLS )
( CLANKlNG )
( electricity crackling )
( indistinct shouting )
( CREATURE roaring )
( SANDER yelling )
I think that was Sander .
Yeah .
( SCREECHlNG ) ( GASPS )
Gross . Oh , no !
Get it !
You see it ?
Where 'd it go ?
There !
Get back !
( SQUEALlNG )
Don 't . Don 't touch it .
( CLATTERS )
Did you hear that ?
Yeah .
( RATTLlNG )
( CLANKlNG )
( SCREECHlNG )
( breathing heavily )
( GROWLlNG in distance )
( GROWLlNG GETS LOUDER )
( ROARS )
( GROWLlNG )
( SCREECHlNG )
( screaming )
Kate .
Sander . Wait .
So what ?
It 'll freeze out there .
And if it doesn 't ?
If it makes it out of here , millions of people could die .
It 's got nowhere to go .
Yes , it does .
( engine sputtering )
Come on .
All right .
What ?
What happened to Lars ?
We didn 't kill him .
( BOTH panting )
Come on .
( SPACESHlP powering UP )
Run ! Run !
( screaming )
Kate !
Kate ?
( air hissing )
( device humming )
( GRUNTS )
( screaming )
( yelling )
( panting )
( SCREECHlNG )
( GRUNTlNG )
Kate !
( POWERlNG DOWN )
So what do we do now ?
There 's a Russian station
about 50 miles from here .
We should have enough gas .
We 're gonna make it back , okay ?
Okay .
Let 's go .
I 'll put this in the back .
You know how I knew you were human
when you showed up back at base ?
No .
Your earring .
It was your other ear .
Kate ... Kate , what are you doing ?
Let 's talk about this .
Talk to me .
Kate .
Kate !
No !
( speaking norwegian )
Hello ?
Edvard ?
Hello !
( shouting in norwegian )
( GUNSHOTS )
Lars !
( speaking norwegian )
( helicopter BLADES whirring )
( panting )